In this segment, I want to give a few
examples of stream ciphers that are used in practice.
在这一部分，我想举几个实践中用到的流密码的例子。
I'm gonna start with two old
examples that actually are not
我打算以两个过时的流密码例子开头，实际上它们已经不
supposed to be used in new systems.
But nevertheless, they're still fairly
应该被用在新的系统中。但是尽管如此，他们仍然相当
widely used, and so I just want to mention
the names so that you're familiar with
广泛地被使用着，所以我只想提及它们的名字以便于你们能熟悉这些概念
these concepts. The first stream cipher I
want to talk about is called RC4, designed
我想说的第一个流密码是于1987年被设计出来的被称为RC4，
back in 1987. And I'm only gonna give you
the high-level description of it, and then,
我只打算做一个高阶的描述
we'll talk about some weaknesses of RC4
and leave it at that. So RC4 takes a
然后我们将会谈论RC4的一些缺点，仅此而已。
variable size seed, here I just gave
as an example where it would take 128
RC4采用一个大小可变的种子，在这里
我只举一个采用128比特的种子作为例子
bits as the seed size, which would then
be used as the key for the stream cipher.
这个种子会被用作流密码的密钥。
The first thing it does, is it expands the
128-bit secret key into 2,048 bits, which
首先，CR4流密码先将128比特的密码扩展为2048比特，
are gonna be used as the internal state
for the generator. And then, once it's done
并将被扩展后的密码将作为生成器的内部状态。
this expansion, it basically executes a
very simple loop, where every iteration of
然后一旦它完成了扩展
基本上就开始执行一个非常简单的循环
this loop outputs one byte of output. So,
essentially, you can run the generator for
每次循环输出一个字节。所以，本质上你可以在任何时候
as long as you want, and generate one byte
at a time. Now RC4 is actually, as I said,
运行生成器,每次运行输出一个字节。现在RC4确实是像我说的那样
fairly popular. It's used in the HTTPS
protocol quite commonly actually.
相当流行。实际上它经常被用在HTTPS协议上。
These days, for example, Google uses RC4 in its
HTTPS. It's also used in WEP as we
例如，如今的谷歌在它的HTTPS协议上就使用了RC4,
discussed in the last segment, but of
course in WEP, it's used incorrectly and
就像我们在上一部分谈论的那样,它也被应用在WEP上,被错误和
it's completely insecure the way it's used
inside of WEP. So over the years,
以不安全的方式在WEP的内部使用。所以这些年来，
some weaknesses have been found in RC4, and as a
result, it's recommended that new projects
RC4的一些缺点已经被人们发现.于是,在新的工程中并不建议使用RC4
actually not use RC4 but rather use a more
modern pseudo-random generator as we'll
而是使用一种更加现代化的伪随机密码产生器,就像我们将要
discuss toward the end of the segment. So
let me just mention two of the weaknesses.
在最后一部分讨论的那样。所以我在此就提一下它的两个缺点，
So the first one is, it's kind of bizarre
basically, if you look at the second byte
第一个缺点，也是有点奇怪的，如果你注意到RC4输出的
of the output of RC4. It turns out the
second byte is slightly biased. If RC4 was
第二个字节，就会发现它是有轻微偏差的。如果RC4是
completely random, the probability that the
second byte happens to be equal to zero
完全随机的，第二个字节碰巧等于零的概率
would be exactly one over 256. There are
256 possible bytes, the probability that
将正好是1/256。一共有256种可能的字节，
it's zero should be one over 256. It so
happens that for RC4 the probability is
它是零的可能性应该是1/256。
然而对于RC4而言，概率恰恰是2/256
actually two over 256, which means that if
you use the RC4 output to encrypt a
那就意味着，如果你使用RC4的输出来加密一个消息,
message the second byte is likely to not
be encrypted at all. In other words it'll
加密一个消息,它的第二个字节可能根本不会被加密。换句话说
be XOR-ed with zero with twice the
probability that it's supposed to.
它与0异或的概率将会是原本概率的两倍
So two over 256, instead of one over 256.
And by the way I should say that there's
所以是2/256，而不是1/256。顺便说一下，应该说
nothing special about the second byte. It
turns out the first and the third bytes
第二个字节并没有什么特别之处。这就使得第一和第三个字节
are also biased. And in fact it's now
recommended that if you're gonna use RC4,
也产生了偏差。实际上,如果你打算使用RC4，更为推荐的做法是
what you should do is ignore basically the
first 256 bytes of the output and just
你应该忽视第一组的256字节的输出，而直接
start using the output of the generator
starting from byte 257. The first couple
从第257个字节开始使用产生器的输出。前几个
of bytes turned out to be biased, so you
just ignore them. The second attack that
字节是有偏差的,而你只需要忽它们。第二种攻击是
was discovered is that in fact if you look
at a very long output of RC4 it so happens
如果你考虑一个非常长的RC4的输出，而它正好
that you're more likely to get the
sequence 00. In other words, you're more
可能会得到一个‘00’序列。换句话说，你更
likely to get sixteen bits, two bytes of
zero, zero, than you should. Again, if RC4
可能会得到16比特,即两个字节的'00',这比你本应得到的要多。再说，如果RC4
was completely random the probability of
seeing zero, zero would be exactly 1/256
得到0的概率是完全随机的，
则得到00的概率将正好是1/256的平方
squared. It turns out RC4 is a little
biased and the bias is 1/256 cubed. It
因此使得RC4有一点偏差,而偏离率是1/256^3。
turns out this bias actually starts after
several giga bytes of data are produced by
事实证明这种偏离实际上是在RC4生成几千兆字节的数据之后开始的。
RC4. But nevertheless, this is something
that can be used to predict the generator
无论怎么说，这是可以用来预测产生器的
and definitely it can be used to
distinguish the output of the generator
更可以被用来
从一个真正随机的序列中辨别产生器的输出
from a truly random sequence. Basically the
fact that zero, zero appears more often
基本上，有更多的“00”出现
than it should is the distinguisher. And
then in the last segment we talked about
是区分二者的关键。在前面最近一部分，我们讨论了
related-key attacks that were used to
attack WEP, that basically say that
被用来攻击WEP的相关密钥攻击，基本上是说
if one uses keys that are closely related
to one another then it's actually possible
如果一个人使用的密钥与另一个人使用的是彼此密切相关的话，那么就很可能
to recover the root key. So these are the
weaknesses that are known of RC4 and, as a
还原出原始密钥。所以这些都是已知的RC4的弱点。所以最后的结论是
result, it's recommended that new systems
actually not use RC4 and instead use a
新的系统并不建议使用RC4，
而是使用一种现代化的伪随机序列生成器。
modern pseudo-random generator. Okay,
second example I want to give you is a
好了，我想举的第二个例子是一个
badly broken stream cipher that's used for
encrypting DVD movies. When you buy a DVD
被用于加密DVD电影，已经被严重破解的流密码
in the store, the actual movie is
encrypted using a stream cipher called the
当你在商店里买一部DVD，
真正的电影内容被一种称为影片加密系统（CSS）的流密码
content scrambling system, CSS. CSS turns
out to be a badly broken stream cipher,
加密了。CSS被证明是一种已经被严重破解的流密码
and we can very easily break it, and I
want to show you how the attack algorithm
我们能够很轻易地破解它，并且我想向你们展示一下这个攻击算法是怎么
works. We're doing it so you can see an
example of an attack algorithm, but in
工作的。我们自己做一遍所以你们可以看到个算法攻击的例子
fact, there are many systems out there
that basically use this attack to decrypt
而事实上，有很多系统基本上都使用这种攻击方式来解密
encrypted DVDs. So the CSS stream cipher
is based on something that hardware
被加密的DVD。CSS流密码是在基于一些
designers like. It's designed to be a
hardware stream cipher that is supposed to
硬件设施的基础上设计的。它被设计成一种硬件流密码，这种流密码是
be easy to implement in hardware, and is
based on a mechanism called a linear
容易在硬件中实现的和基于线性反馈移位寄存器的
feedback shift register. So a linear
feedback shift register is basically a register
所以一个线性反馈移位寄存器基本上就是一个
that consists of cells where
each cell contains one bit. Then basically
由一些单元小格组成的，每个小格储存一个比特的寄存器。然后
what happens is there are these taps into
certain cells, not all the cells, certain
有一些接口与这些单元小格连接，并不是所有的小格都被接口连接
positions are called taps. And then these
taps feed into an XOR and then at
这些特定的位置被称为接口。然后这些接口被输入到一个异或门，然后在
every clock cycle, the shift register
shifts to the right. The last bit falls off
每一个时钟周期内，移位寄存器就会进行一次右移。最后一位被去掉
and then the first bit becomes the result
of this XOR. So you can see that
第一位就成了异或门的输出。所以你可以看到
this is a very simple mechanism to implement, and in hardware takes very few
这是一个很容易实现的机制，在硬件上只需要很少的
transistors. Just the shift right, the
last bit falls off and the first bit just
晶体管就能实现。只要向右移,最后一个比特被移出,先前的异或
becomes the XOR of the previous
bits. So the seed for this LFSR
的结果就成为了第一比特位。所以这个LFSR的种子
basically, is the initial state of the LFSR.
就是LFSR的最初的状态。
And it is the basis of a number of stream
ciphers. So here are some examples. So, as
这是许多流密码的基础来源。这里有一些例子。所以，
I said, DVD encryption uses two LFSRs.
I'll show you how that works in just a
正如我说的那样，DVD加密运用了两次LFSR。我将快速给你们展示那是怎样工作的。
second. GSM encryption, these are
algorithms called A51 and A52. And that
GSM加密采用的算法被称为A51和A52，
uses three LFSRs. Bluetooth encryption is
an algorithm called, E zero. These are all
它使用三次LFSRs，还有蓝牙加密算法--E0，这些都是
stream ciphers, and that uses four LFSRs.
Turns out all of these are badly broken,
流密码，而且使用四次LFSRs。结果这些算法都被完全破解了
and actually really should not be trusted
for encrypting traffic, but they're all
在实际加密通信中并不可信，但是他们都是
implemented in hardware, so it's a little
difficult now to change what the hardware
在硬件上实现的,所以现在要改变硬件的工作机制是有难度的。
does. But the simplest of these, CSS,
actually has a cute attack on it, so let
但是这里面最简单的是：针对CSS，实际上有一个聪明的攻击方法，让
me show you how the attack works. So,
let's describe how CSS actually works. So,
我给你们展示这个攻击是怎么运作的。让我们让我们描述CSS实际上是如何运作的。
the key for CSS is five bytes, namely 40
bits, five times eight is 40 bits. The
CSS的密钥是五个字节,即40比特位,5乘8等于40位
reason they had to limit themselves to
only 40 bits is that DVD encryption was
它们被限制为40位的原因是DVD加密方式是被设计
designed at a time where U.S. Export
regulations only allowed for export of
在美国出口条例只允许出口
crpyto algorithms where the key was
only 40 bits. So the designers of CSS were
40位加密算法的密钥的时期。因此，CSS的设计者
already limited to very, very short keys.
Just 40 bit keys. So, their design works
将密钥限制的很短,很短,只有40位。因此,它们的设计如下，
as follows. Basically, CSS uses two
LFSR's. One is a 17-bit LFSR. In other words,
大体上,CSS用两个LFSR。一个是17位的LFSR,换句话说，
the register contains
17 bits. And the other one is a 25-bit LFSR,
寄存器容量是17比特。另一个是25位的LSFR，
it's a little bit longer, 25-bit
LFSR. And the way these LFSRs are seeded
25位的LFSR要更大一点。这些LSFR被植入的方式如下
is as follows. So the key for the
encryption, basically looks as follows.
用于加密的密钥，基本上看上去是这样的
You start off with a one, and you concatenate to it the first two bytes of
以1作为开头，把它与密钥的前两个字节连接。
the key. And that's the initial state of the LFSR.
这就是这个LFSR的初始状态。
And then the second LFSR basically is intitialized the same way.
然后，第二个LFSR基本上是同样的方式初始化。
One concatenated the last three bytes of
the key. And that's
一个寄存器连接最后的三个字节
loaded into the initial state of the LFSR.
You can see that the first two bytes are
并被装载进了LFSR的最初状态。你可以看到前两个字节
sixteen bits, plus leading one, that's
seventeen bits overall, whereas the second
即16位，加上开头的1位,一共17比特位。同时第二个LFSR
LFSR is 24 bits plus one which is 25 bits.
And you notice we used all five bits of
是24位再加一个是25位。你可以注意到我们使用了密钥的全部五位。
the key. So then these LFSRs are basically
run for eight cycles, so they generate
因此，这些LFSR基本上运行8个循环，它们产生
eight bits of output. And then they go
through this adder that does basically
8比特的输出。然后，它们经过加法器做
addition modulo 256. Yeah so this is an
addition box, modulo 256. There's one more
模256的加法运算。因此这是一个模256的加法计算器。
technical thing that happens. In fact let's
actually—also added is the carry from the
这里还有一点是，加法要考虑前面分组的进位，
previous block. But that is not so
important. That's a detail that's not so
不过这不是那么重要，它只是一个不怎么相关的细节。
relevant. OK, so every block, you notice
we're doing addition modulo 256 and
对于每一个分组，我们需要注意做模256加法运算时
we're ignoring the carry, but the carry is
basically added as a zero or a one to the
忽略了进位，进位是以0或1
addition of the next block. Okay? And then
basically this output one byte per round.
进入到下一分组。并且每次循环将输出一个字节。
Okay, and then this byte is then of course
used, XOR-ed with the appropriate
当然,这个字节同电影里的字节进行异或加密。
byte of the movie that's being encrypted.
Okay, so it's a very simple stream
它是一个非常简单的流密码，
cipher, it takes very little hardware to
implement. It will run fast, even on very
只需要很少硬件来实现的。它运行地非常快，甚至
cheap hardware and it will encrypt movies.
So it turns out this is easy to break
在非常低廉的硬件上也能够快速加密电影
因此导致只需要2的17次方次的尝试就可以将其破解
in time roughly two to the seventeen. Now let me show you how.
现在让我来给你们演示一下怎么做的。
So suppose you
intercept the movies, so here we have an
现在假设你截获了一部电影，这里有
encrypted movie that you want to decrypt.
So let's say that this is all encrypted so
你想要破解的加密电影。我们假设电影全都被加密了
you have no idea what's inside of here.
However, it so happens that just because
你不知道里面是什么。然而,碰巧由于
DVD encryption is using MPEG files, it so
happens if you know of a prefix of the
DVD加密是用MPEG文件，如果你碰巧知道明文的前缀，
plaintext, let's just say maybe this is
twenty bytes. Well, we know if you
我们假设它是20个字节的。那么我们知道如果你
XOR these two things together, so in other words, you do the XOR here,
对这两个进行异或，换句话说，你在这进行了异或
what you'll get is the initial segment of the PRG. So, you'll get the
你将会得到PRG（即：伪随机码发生器）的
最初的部分。因此，你将会得到
first twenty bytes of the output of CSS,
the output of this PRG. Okay, so now
CSS输出的前20个字节也就是PRG的输出。
here's what we're going to do. So we have
the first twenty bytes of the output. Now
我们有了20个字节的输出，那么接下来要做的就是
we do the following. We try all two to the
seventeen possible values of the first
尝试2的17次方个全部可能第一个LFSR的值。
LFSR. Okay? So two to the seventeen
possible values. So for each value, so for
因此，对于2的17次方种可能的
each of these two to the seventeen initial
values of the LFSR, we're gonna run the
LFSR寄存器的初始值，我们将运行
LFSR for twenty bytes, okay? So we'll
generate twenty bytes of outputs from this
这些LFSR来产生20个字节。因此我们将从假设的2的17次方个可能的初始设置中
first LFSR, assuming—for each one of the
two to the seventeen possible settings
生成第一个LFSR的20个字节
Now, remember we have the full output of
the CSS system. So what we can do is we
现在，记得我们有全部的CSS输出系统。现在我们可以做的是
can take this output that we have. And
subtract it from the twenty bites that we
我们可以把得到的输出减去从第一个LFSR产生的20个字节。
got from the first LFSR, and if in fact our
guess for the initial state of the first
事实上，如果我们对初始状态的猜测是正确的，
LFSR is correct, what we should get
is the first twenty-byte output of the
我们将得到的是第二个LFSR产生的前20个字节
second LFSR. Right? Because that's by
definition what the output of the CSS
对吗？因为这是根据CSS系统的定义而输出的。
system is. Now, it turns out that looking
at a 20-byte sequence, it's very easy
现在，事实上20个字节队列，非常容易
to tell whether this 20-byte sequence
came from a 25-bit LFSR or not. If it
辨别出来它是不是来自一个25字节的LFSR。如果
didn't, then we know that our guess
for the 17-bit LFSR was
不是，我们就知道我们的17位LFSR的假设是错误的，
incorrect and then we move on to the next
guess for the 17-bit LFSR and
并且我们进行下一步的假设，
the next guess and so on and so forth.
Until eventually we hit the right initial
下下步的假设，以此类推。直到最终我们得到正确的
state for the 17-bit LFSR, and
then we'll actually get, we'll see that
17位LFSR的初始状态。然后我们事实上会得到的，我们将会看到
the 20 bytes that we get as the
candidate output for the 25-bit LFSR is
得到的这20个字节可能的输出情况。
in fact a possible output for a 25-bit LFSR. And then, not only will we have
事实上，是25位LFSR的一种可能的输出情况。这样，我们不仅
learned the correct initial state for the
17-bit LFSR, we will have also
学会了正确的17位LFSR的初始状态，我们还
learned the correct initial state of the
25-bit LFSR. And then we can predict the
学会了25位LFSR的初始状态。我们可以预测
remaining outputs of CSS, and of course,
using that, we can then decrypt the rest of
剩余的CSS的输出。
当然，用这种方法，我们可以破解电影的剩余部分
the movie. We can actually recover the
remaining plaintext. Okay. This is
进而可以还原整个明文。
things that we talked about before. So, I
said this a little quick, but hopefully,
我们以前已经讲过这个了。因此，我说的快了一点点，但愿还算
it was clear. We're also going to be doing
a homework exercise on this type of stream
清晰。我们在流密码这部分有一道作业题，
ciphers and you'll kind of get the point
of how these attack algorithms
通过这道题你将会有掌握攻击算法是怎样做的。
work. And I should mention that there are
many open-source systems now that actually
我要提醒的是有许多开源系统，现在都是
use this method to decrypt CSS-encrypted
data. Okay, so now that we've seen two
用这种方法破解CSS密码的。好，现在我们看完了两个简单的例子，
weak examples, let's move on to better
examples, and in particular the better
让我们看看更好的例子，有个来自于eStreamd的
pseudo-random generators come from what's
called the eStream Project. This is a
更好的伪随机函数产生器。这个
project that concluded in 2008, and they
qualify basically five different stream
项目在2008年完成了，给出了5种不同的流密码，
ciphers, but here I want to present just
one. So first of all the parameters for
但是这里我只想讲一种。因此，首先，这些流密码的参数
these stream ciphers are a little
different than what we're used to. So these
与我们以前用过的有一点不一样。
stream ciphers as normal they have a seed.
But in addition they also have, what's
这些流密码和其他的正常的一样有种子。此外还有一个
called a nonce and we'll see what a
nonce is used for in just a minute. So
被称为随机数的，我们马上来看随机数是用来干嘛的。
they take two inputs a seed and a nonce.
We'll see what the nonce is used for in
它们需要输入一个种子和一个随机数。我们来看如何输入随机数。
just a second. And the of course they
produce a very large output, so n here is
理所应当，它们会产生一个非常大的输出，
much, much, much bigger than s. Now, when
I say nonce, what I mean is a value that's
这里的n远远大于s.现在,当我说到随机数的时候,就是指只要密钥确定,它的值
never going to repeat as long as the key
is fixed. And I'll explain that in more
就永远不变。我接下来将会详细解释。
detail in just a second. But for now, just
think of it as a unique value that never
而现在,只需要把它看作是一个独一无二的值
repeats as long as the key is the same.
And so of course once you have this PRG,
只要密钥确定，它就永不重复。当然，一旦你有了PRG，
you would encrypt, you get a stream cipher
just as before, except now as you see, the
你就能加密像之前流密码加密一样，
除了你现在看到的，PRG需要密钥和随机数
PRG takes as input both the key and the
nonce. And the property of the nonce is
作为输入。而随机数是一对的(k,r)
that the pair, k comma r, so the key comma
the nonce, is never—never repeats. It's
所以，切记切记：密钥,随机数,永远永远不会重复。
never used more than once. So the bottom
line is that you can reuse the key, reuse
它是一次一密，但底线是你可以重复利用密钥。
the key, because the nonce makes the
pair unique, because k and r are only
因为随机数让它们独一无二，因为k和r
used once. I'll say they're unique. Okay
so this nonce is kind of a cute trick that
只用一次，我说它们是唯一。
这个随机数是一个“狡猾”的小花招
saves us the trouble of moving to a new
key every time. Okay, so the particular
避免了我们每次更新密钥的麻烦。好，这个特殊的
example from the eStream that I want to
show you is called Salsa twenty. It's a
来自eStream的例子正是我想给你们展示的Salsa20.
stream cipher that's designed for both
software implementations and hardware
它是一个特别设计的在硬件和软件设施均可用的流密码。
implementations. It's kind of interesting.
You realize that some stream ciphers are
这有点意思，大家知道到一些流密码是为
designed for software, like RC4.
Everything it does is designed to make
软件而设计的，比如RC4.所有关于它的设计
software implementation run fast, whereas
other stream ciphers are designed for
都是为了让软件更快地运行。而其他的流密码是为硬件而设计的，
hardware, like CSS, using an LFSR that's
particularly designed to make hardware
比如CSS，运用了一个特别为低廉硬件定制的LFRS寄存器
implementations very cheap. It's also, the
nice thing about that is that it's
关于它的一件比较好的事情是
designed so that it's both easy to
implement it in hardware and its software
它被这样设计所以它对硬件和软件都有利，
implementation is also very fast. So let
me explain how Salsa works. Well, Salsa
运行速度都快。让我来解释Salsa是怎么工作的。好，
takes either 128 or 256-bit keys. I'll
only explain the 128-bit version of Salsa.
Salsa 输入128位或者256位的密钥，我将只解释128位版本的Salsa。
So this is the seed. And then it also
takes a nonce, just as before, which
这就是种子。需要输入一个随机数，像刚才一样，
happens to be 64 bits. And then it'll
generate a large output. Now, how does it
也是64位。然后会产生一个巨大的输出。现在看，它是
actually work? Well, the function itself
is defined as follows. Basically, given
怎么工作的呢？函数定义如下。基本上
the key and the nonce, it will generate a
very long, well, a long pseudorandom
给定的密钥和随机数，它将会产生一个很长,很长的伪随机序列，
sequence, as long as necessary. And it'll do
it by using this function that I'll denote by
相当的长,如果有必要的话。我将通过使用的函数我把它记作H来实现.
H. This function H takes three inputs.
Basically the key. Well, the seed k,
这个H函数需要三个输入。密钥，种子k,
the nonce r, and then a counter that
increments from step to step. So it goes
随机数r,一个计数器一步一步计数。
from zero to one, two, three, four as long as
we need it to be. Okay? So basically,
它从0到1，2,3,4,直到我们需要。明白了吗？
by evaluating this H on this k r, but using
this incrementing counter, we can get a
所以通过评估H函数和(k,r),用递增计数器，我们
sequence that's as long as we want. So all
I have to do is describe how this function
得到我们想要的队列。我们全部需要做的就是描述
H works. Now, let me do that here for you.
The way it works is as follows. Well, we
这个函数H是怎么工作的。现在，让我来描述一下。它是按以下方式工作的，
start off by expanding the states into
something quite large which is 64 bytes
开始先把状态扩充至64个字节长，
long, and we do that as follows. Basically
we stick a constant at the beginning, so
我们按以下方式做。我们在刚开始先定义一个常数，
there's tao zero, these are four bytes,
it's a four byte constant, so the spec for
τ0是4字节，它是个4字节常量，Salsa给定了
Salsa basically gives you the value for
tao zero. Then we put k in which is
τ0的值。然后，我们把k放在
sixteen bytes. Then we put another
constant. Again, this is four bytes. And
16字节的地方。然后我们把另一个常量，也是四字节的放进去。
as I said, the spec basically specifies
what this fixed constant is. Then we put
正如我所说，说明书上也定义了这个常量。
the nonce, which is eight bytes. Then we
put the index. This is the counter zero,
我们取8字节的随机数，再取索引表。这是计数器
one, two, three, four, which is another
eight bytes. Then we put another constant
0,1,2,3,4,是另外8比特。然后我们取另外一个常量
tau two, which is another four bytes.
Then we put the key again, this is another
τ2,也是四字节的。再取密钥，这是另外一个
sixteen bytes. And then finally we put the
third constant, tau three, which is
16字节的。最后我们取第三个常量，τ3,
another four bytes. Okay so as I said, if you
sum these up, you see that you get 64
还是4字节的。如我所说，如果你把这些加起来，你将会看到
bytes. So basically we've expanded the key
and the nonce and the counter into 64
你得到字节数。我们已经扩展了密钥，随机数，计数器为64字节，
bytes. Basically the key is repeated twice
I guess. And then what we do is we apply a
并且密钥重复了两次。接下来我们要用一个函数
function, I'll call this functional little h.
Okay, so we apply this function, little h.
我们把这个函数称为h。
And this is a function that's one to one
so it maps 64 bytes to 64 bytes. It's a
这个函数是由64字节到64字节一一对应的
completely invertible function, okay? So
this function h is, as I say, it's an
它是一个完全可逆的函数。这个函数h，正如我所说的，是一个可逆函数。
invertable function. So given the input
you can get the output and given the
因此，给定一个输入你将得到输出，
output you can go back to the input. And
it's designed specifically so it's a- easy
给一个输出将会返回输入。并且它被特殊设计过,因此
to implement in hardware and b- on an x86,
it's extremely easy to implement because
在x86上很容易运行
x86 has this SSE2 instruction set which
supports all the operations you need to do
因为x86有SSE2指令支持操作
for this function. It's very, very fast.
As a result, Salsa has a very fast stream
这个函数。它非常非常地快。总之，Salsa有一个
cipher. And then it does this basically
again and again. So it applies this
非常快的流密码。它不断地做这件事。因此它应用于
function h again and it gets another 64
bytes. And so on and so forth, basically
函数h得到另外的64字节。诸如此类，
it does this ten times. Okay so the whole
thing here, say repeats ten times, so
基本上它要这样做10次，好，这里是全部的，重复10次，
basically apply h ten times. And then by
itself, this is actually not quite random.
因此基本上用h用10次。对它自身来说，它并不是
It's not gonna look random because like we
said, H is completely invertable. So given
随机的，因为正如我们所说的，H是一个完全可逆的。
this final output, it's very easy to
just invert h and then go back to the original
因此给定了最终的输出就非常容易求h的逆，再返回
inputs and then test that the input has
the right structure. So you do one more
原始输入，然后测试输入的正确结构。
thing, which is to basically XOR the
inputs and the final outputs. Actually,
那么我们就再做另外一件事，
把最终输出和输入进行异或。事实上，
sorry. It's not an XOR. It's actually an
addition. So you do an addition word by
对不起，不是异或，实际上是相加。做一字一句地相加。
word. So if there are 64 bytes, you do a
word-by-word addition four bytes at a
因此，如果是64字节，要进行4字节一次地相加，
time, and finally you get the 64-byte
output, and that's it. That's the whole
最终得到64字节的输出，就是结果了。这就是整个
pseudo-random generator. So that, that's
the whole function, little h. And as I
伪随机数发生器。因此，对于整个函数是h,
explained, this whole construction here is
the function big H. And then you evaluate
正如我解释的，整个机制是函数H。然后
big H by incrementing the counter I from
zero, one, two, three onwards. And that
通过递增计数器从0,1,2,3向上来评估函数H。
will give you a pseudo-random sequence
that's as long as you need it to be. And
这样你会得到一个伪随机数发生器只要你需要。
basically, there are no signifigant
attacks on this. This has security that's
基本上在这方面还没有重大的攻击。它的安全系数接近
very close to two to the 128. We'll see
what that means more precisely later on.
2的128次方。我们随后将会讨论更详细的内容。
It's a very fast stream cipher, both in
hardware and in software. And, as far as
它是非常快的流密码，无论在硬件上还是在软件上。就我们而言，
we can tell, it seems to be unpredictable
as required for a stream cipher. So I
它看上去似乎是不可预测的作为流密码，
正如一个流密码需要的那样。
should say that the eStream project
actually has five stream ciphers like
因此为应该说eStream 工程实际上有五个像这样的流密码。
this. I only chose Salsa 'cause I think
it's the most elegant. But I can give you
我只举Salsa的例子我认为最合适的。但是我可以给你们
some performance numbers here. So you can
see, these are performance numbers on a
一些性能参数。这些是在x86机上的2.2Ghz性能值。可以看到这些性能参数，
2.2 gigahertz, you know, x86 type machine.
And you can see that RC4 actually is the
你可以看到RC4事实上是最慢的。
slowest. Because essentially, well it
doesn't really take advantage of the
因为在本质上，它在硬件上并不占优势。
hardware. It only does byte operations.
And so there's a lot of wasted cycles that
它只有字操作，因此有很多浪费的循环没有被用。
aren't being used. But the E-Stream
candidates, both Salsa and other
但是eStream,无论是Salsa还是其他的，
candidate called Sosemanuk. I should say these
are eStream finalists. These are
都被称为Sosemanuk.我认为它们是eStream的优胜者。
actually stream ciphers that are approved
by the eStream project. You can see that
事实上，有很多流密码都获得了eStream项目的批准。你可以看到
they have achieved a significant rate.
This is 643 megabytes per second on this
它们取得了很高的速率。这个架构每秒处理643M字节的数据，
architecture, more than enough for a movie
and these are actually quite impressive
这个速度足以应对电影并且相当令人印象深刻。
rates. And so now you've seen examples of
two old stream ciphers that shouldn't be
因此，现在你已经看到两个老的已经不应该被用到流密码的例子，
used, including attacks on those stream ciphers.
You've seen what the modern stream ciphers
包括流密码的攻击。你已经看到
look like with this nonce. And you
see the performance numbers for these
看起来像随机数的现代流密码。根据现代流密码的性能参数,如果
modern stream ciphers so if you happen to
need a stream cipher you could use one of
你需要使用流密码，你可以使用一种eStream的优胜方案。
the eStream finalists. In particular you
could use something like Salsa.
特别地,你可以用Salsa。